Guide to the Donald Davie Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1946-1995; Series II; 4; (11 boxes)
  - REVIEWS
    - "A Demurral," printed version, The New Republic, 1987 Apr 20 (Box 17, Folder 577)
      Review of The Collected Poems of William Carlos Williams, Volume One: 1909-1939 edited by A. Walton Litz and Christopher MacGowan.
    - Durant, Alan. Ezra Pound: Identity in Crisis, typescript, corrected, [1981] (Box 17, Folder 578)
    - "English and American in Briggflatts ," typescript, corrected (Box 17, Folder 579)
      Review of Briggflatts: An Autobiography by Basil Bunting.
    - "English in Context," printed version, Inquiry, 1980 Apr 21 (Box 17, Folder 580)
      Review of A Writer's Britain: Landscape in Literature by Margaret Drabble.
    - "F. R. Leavis: Voice in the Desert," typescript carbon, corrected, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 581)
      Review of Thought, Words and Creativity by F. R. Leavis.
    - "Fallen Language," clipping of printed version, London Review of Books, 1984 Jun 21 (Box 17, Folder 582)
      Review of The Lords of Limit: Essays on Literature and Ideas by Geoffrey Hill.
    - Fisher, Lois H. A Literary Gazetteer of England; Margaret Drabble. A Writer's Britain: Landscape in Literature; and Frank Morley. Literary Britain: A Reader's Guide to Its Writers and Landmarks, typescript, corrected, [1980] (Box 17, Folder 583)
    - "The Franglais of Criticism; the English of Translation," typescript carbon, corrected, [1983] (Box 17, Folder 584)
      Review of The Formed Trace: The Later Poetry of Ezra Pound by Massimo Bacigalupo; The Tale of the Tribe: Ezra Pound and the Modern Verse Epic by Michael André Bernstein; and Massimo Bacigalupo and Giovanni Giudici's translation of Ezra Pound's Hugh Selwyn Mauberley.
    - "From the Manifest to the Therapeutic," clipping of printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1982 Apr 30 (Box 17, Folder 585)
      Review of Adrian Stokes: With All the Views edited by Peter Robinson.
    - "A Genius and His Limitations," clipping of printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1987 Jun 19 (Box 17, Folder 586)
      Review of John Keats by John Barnard.
    - Gifford, Henry. Poetry in a Divided World, proof, corrected, n.d.
    - Grossman, Allen R. Against Our Vanishing: Winter Conversations with Allen Grossman on the Theory and Practice of Poetry, typescript carbon, corrected, [1981] (Box 17, Folder 587)
    - Gunn, Thom. Selected Poems, 1950-1975; Reginald Gibbons. Roofs, Voices, Roads, clipping of printed version, The New Republic, 1979 Oct 13 (Box 17, Folder 588)
    - Hamburger, Michael. Ownerless Earth, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 589)
    - "Imagined, or Imaginary?," printed version, Inquiry, 1980 Jun 9 (Box 17, Folder 590)
      Review of Imagining America by Peter Conrad.
    - "Lapidary Lucidity," clipping of printed version, The Threepenny Review, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 591)
      Review of Collected Poems of Carl Rakosi.
    - Larkin, Philip, editor. The Oxford Book of Twentieth-Century English Verse, typescript and holograph, corrected, [1973] (Box 17, Folder 592)
    - Lowell, Robert
      - Collected Prose, typescript, corrected, [1987] (Box 17, Folder 593)
      - History; For Lizzie and Harriet; and The Dolphin, typescript carbon, [1973] (Box 17, Folder 594)
    - "A Luckier Chatterton"
      See: "Against Rule and Compass," box 17, folder 568
    - "Off the Assembly Line," printed version, Essays in Criticism, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 595)
      Review of Pope's Dunciad: A Study of Its Meaning by Aubrey L. Williams and Personification in Eighteenth-Century English Poetry by Chester F. Chapin.
    - "One Way to Misread Briggflatts ," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 596)
    - "A Poem for Fordie," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 597)
      Review of The Love of Strangers by Michael Schmidt.
    - "A Poet Seeking Guidance," clipping of printed version, The Guardian, 1983 Mar 17 (Box 17, Folder 598)
      Review of Pound/Ford: The Story of a Literary Friendship edited by Brita Lindberg-Seyersted.
    - Pritchard, William H. Lives of the Modern Poets; Helen Vendler. Part of Nature, Part of Us: Modern American Poets; Jerome Mazzaro. Postmodern American Poetry; Daniel Hoffman, editor. Harvard Guide to Contemporary American Writing, typescript, corrected (Box 17, Folder 599)
    - "Raining," clipping of printed version, London Review of Books, 1983 May 5 (Box 17, Folder 600)
      Review of five Thomas Hardy books.
    - Rakosi, Carl. Collected Poems, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 601)
    - "Reading and Believing"
      Review of The Literary Guide to the Bible edited by Robert Alter and Frank Kermode.
      - Typescript, corrected (2 photocopies), [1987] (Box 17, Folder 602)
      - Printed version, The New Republic, 1987 Oct 26 (Box 17, Folder 602)
    - Robinson, Ian. Chaucer and the English Tradition, holograph, corrected, [1972] (Box 17, Folder 603)
    - "The Saturated Line"
      - Typescript, corrected, [1988] (Box 17, Folder 604)
      - Clipping of printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1988 Dec 23 (Box 17, Folder 605)
        Review of To Urania: Selected Poems, 1965-1985 by Joseph Brodsky.
    - Stock, Noel. The Life of Ezra Pound, typescript, corrected (Box 17, Folder 606)
    - "Transatlantic Exacerbations," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 607)
      Review of Love-Hate Relations: A Study of Anglo-American Sensibilities by Stephen Spender.
    - "The Twain Not Meeting," typescript (photocopy), n.d. (Box 17, Folder 608)
      Review of Coming to Terms by Josephine Miles and The Venetian Vespers by Anthony Hecht.
    - "The Universe of Ezra Pound," typescript (mimeograph), corrected, [1971] (Box 17, Folder 609)
      Review of The Pound Era by Hugh Kenner.
    - Warshaw, Howard. Drawings on Drawing, typescript, corrected (Box 17, Folder 610)
    - "The Wasteland Ltd."
      Review of The Letters of T. S. Eliot: Volume I, 1898-1922 edited by Valerie Eliot and Eliot's New Life by Lyndall Gordon.
      - Typescript, corrected, [1988] (Box 17, Folder 611)
      - Printed version, The New Republic, 1988 Dec 12 (Box 17, Folder 611)
    - Wilson, Angus. The Strange Ride of Rudyard Kipling: His Life and Works, typescript, corrected, [1978] (Box 17, Folder 612)
    - "Wintry Talent," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 613)
      Review of Wisdom and Wilderness: The Achievements of Yvor Winters by Dick Davis.
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - "Anthologies," list, holograph, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 614)
    - "Basil Bunting and Religious Orthodoxy," letter to the editor, clipping of printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, 1986 Aug 22 (Box 17, Folder 615)
    - "Compatibility," letter to the editor, clipping (photocopy) of printed version, London Review of Books, 1994 Jun 23 (Box 17, Folder 616)
    - "The English Idea of Russian Fiction Since 1828," dissertation, typescript carbon, corrected, in volume, 1950 Oct (Box 18, Folder 617)
    - Poetry Nation Review, editorials, typescript and printed versions, 1977-81, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 618)
    - "Pound Debate," letter to the editor, clipping of printed version, The Stanford Daily, 1976 May 11 (Box 19, Folder 619)
    - "Pound's Anti-Semitism," letter to the editor, typescript, corrected, Midstream, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 620)
    - [Response to Neil Powell], letter to the editor, typescript, corrected, Poetry Nation Review, [1989] Dec 27 (Box 19, Folder 621)
    - [Response to Richard Caddel and Peter Makin], letter to the editor, typescript, corrected, The Times Literary Supplement, [1986] (Box 19, Folder 622)
      With clippings of letters to the editor by Caddel and Makin.
      See also: Articles, "God in Recent Poetry," box 9, folder 393
    - [Response to Tom Paulin], letter to the editor, typescript, corrected, London Review of Books, 1984 May 19 (Box 19, Folder 623)
    - Translations of poems by others, drafts, typescript, corrected, 1981, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 624)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Alter, Robert. "A Poet of the Holocaust," printed version (mimeograph), Commentary, 1973 Nov, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 625)
    - The Association for the Apostolic Ministry (Australia). "Proceedings of the 1994 Conference on 'The Family in Christian Tradition,'" printed version (Box 19, Folder 626)
    - Bell, Vereen and Laurence Lerner. On Modern Poetry: Essays Presented to Donald Davie. Clippings of reviews, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 627)
    - Bergonzi, Bernard. "The Poetry of Donald Davie," printed version, The Critical Quarterly, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 628)
    - Bradbury, P. A. "Clearing a Space: The Poetry and Criticism of Donald Davie," typescript (fragment) (Box 19, Folder 629)
    - Braybrooke, Neville. "The Wise Men," poem, typescript carbon, corrected, [1981] (Box 19, Folder 630)
      Inscribed to DD, 1981 Apr 19.
    - Brown, Mark. "Ivor Gurney's Leaves of Grass ," typescript, corrected, [1995] (Box 19, Folder 631)
      With envelope postmarked 1995 Jan 11.
    - Crozier, Andrew. "Remembering Carl Rakosi: A Conjectural Reconstruction of The Beasts (Box 19, Folder 632)
    - Dalby, J. M. M. "The Book of Common Prayer and Its Role in the Church of England," lecture, typescript, 1992 Mar 21 (Box 19, Folder 633)
    - Davie, Mark. "The Contexts of the Griselda Story in Boccaccio and Petrarch," typescript (Box 19, Folder 633a)
    - Dembo, L. S. "The Poetry of Carl Rakosi," photocopy of printed version, The Iowa Review (Vol. II, No. 7, 1971), annotated by Donald Davie, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 634)
    - Grant, Michael. "Subject and Person," typescript (Box 19, Folder 635)
    - Hill, Geoffrey
      - "The Mystery of the Charity of Charles Péguy," clipping of printed version, The Times Literary Supplement, annotated by Donald Davie, 1983 Feb 4 (Box 19, Folder 636)
      - "Our Word Is Our Bond," printed version (photocopy), Agenda, annotated by Donald Davie (Box 19, Folder 637)
    - Hoffman, Daniel. "The Translators' Party," clipping of printed version, The Southern Review (Box 19, Folder 638)
      Inscribed to DD.
    - Hughes, Ted. "Rain-Charm for the Duchy," poem, clipping of printed version, The Observer, 1984 Dec 23 (Box 19, Folder 639)
    - Jarman, Mark. "Proposal: Demonology by Philip Wilby and Mark Jarman," typescript (photocopy) (Box 19, Folder 640)
    - Jones, Richard
      - "Sing Doo Wah Diddy with Derrida," typepscript, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 641)
      - "The Very Dead of Winter: Notes Towards an Enquiry into English Poetry After Eliot," typescript, annotated by Donald Davie, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 642)
    - Kuhrt, David. "The Divination of Reality: The Conflict Between Mythical and Instrumental, Oral and Written Narratives, and the Future of Poetry," typescript, corrected (Box 19, Folder 643)
    - Martz, Louis L., editor. H. D. Collected Poems, 1912-1944, photocopy of printed version, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 644)
    - Montague, John and Liam Miller, editors. A Tribute to Austin Clarke on His Seventieth Birthday, 9 May 1966, photocopies of p. 7-23 (Box 19, Folder 645)
    - Myers, Diana. "Mandel'shtam's Horseshoe Finder, printed version (fragment) (Box 19, Folder 646)
    - Pritchett, V. S. "Appalachian Spring," clipping of printed version, The New York Review, 1982 Jan 21 (Box 19, Folder 647)
    - Rakosi, Carl
      - "George Oppen, The Last Days," typescript (photocopy), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 648)
      - "The Old Poet's Tale," printed version (photocopy), Scripsi (1985), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 649)
      - Selected Poems (Norfolk, Conn.: New Direction, 1941). Photocopies of pages, annotated by Donald Davie, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 650)
    - Schmidt, Michael
      - "Editorial Note," proof, annotated by Donald Davie, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 651)
      - "The Fairy Godmother and Her Bosses," clipping of printed version, The Listener, annotated by Donald Davie, 1977 Oct 20 (Box 19, Folder 652)
      - Poems, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 653)
    - Seymour-Smith, Martin. "The Literary Situation--II," printed version (mimeograph), Departure, 1955, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 654)
      Review of "Homage to William Cowper," poem by DD.
    - Shapiro, Alan
      - "The Early Seventies and J. V. Cunningham," essay, typescript (Box 19, Folder 655)
      - Poems, typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 656)
    - Sisson, C. H.
      - "Appleby," poem, typescript (photocopy), 1975 Jun (Box 19, Folder 657)
      - "Conceptions More Sublime," photocopy of printed version, The New York Times Book Review (1989 Feb 26), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 658)
      - "Yeats Revisited," photocopy of printed version, The New Criterion (1989 Jun), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 659)
    - Smith, Stevie
      - "Girls!," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 660)
      - "Not Waving But Drowning," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 660)
    - Thomas, R. S. Poems, typescript (mimeograph) (2 copies), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 661)
    - Tomlinson, Charles. Poems, typescript carbon, 1951, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 662)
    - Watts, Isaac. Death and Heaven or the Last Enemy Conquered and Separate Spirits Made Perfect, photocopy, annotated by Donald Davie (Box 19, Folder 663-664)
    - Winters, Yvor
      - "At the San Francisco Airport," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 665)
      - "By the Road to the Air-Base," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 665)
    - Unidentified
      - Empty folder (Box 19, Folder 666)
      - "For Donald Davie," poem, typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 667)
      - "Grace Darling," poem, typescript, corrected, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 668)
- Journals and Notebooks, 1947-1995; Series III; 3; (8 boxes)
  Series III, Journals and Notebooks, is arranged chronologically. Each item is a holograph volume.
  - "Journal Vol. I", 1947-49 (Box 20, Folder 669)
  - "Campbell's Imperial Diary for 1949" (Box 20, Folder 670)
  - "Journal Vol. II", 1950 (Box 20, Folder 671)
  - "Journal Vol. III", 1950 Sep-Dec (Box 20, Folder 672)
  - "Journal Vol. IV", 1951 Jan-Aug (Box 20, Folder 673)
  - "Journal Vol. V", 1951 Aug-52 Jan (Box 21, Folder 674)
  - "Journal Vol. VII", 1952 Sep-53 Jan (Box 21, Folder 675)
  - "Journal Vol. VIII", 1953 Feb-54 Feb (Box 21, Folder 676)
  - "Journal Vol. IX", 1954 Feb-Sep (Box 21, Folder 677)
  - "Journal Vol. XI", 1955 May-56 May (Box 21, Folder 678)
  - "Journal Vol. XII", 1956 May-Nov (Box 21, Folder 679)
  - "Journal Vol. XIII", 1956 Nov-57 May (Box 22, Folder 680)
  - "Journal Vol. XIV", 1957 May-Nov (Box 22, Folder 681)
  - "Journal Vol. XV", 1959 Mar-Nov (Box 22, Folder 682)
  - "Journal Vol. XVI", 1959 Nov-60 May (Box 22, Folder 683)
  - "Journal Vol. XVII", 1960 May-Nov (Box 22, Folder 684)
  - "Journal Vol. XVIII", 1960 Nov-61 Jun (Box 22, Folder 685)
  - "Journal Vol. XIX", 1961 Jun-Dec (Box 23, Folder 686)
  - "Vol. XX", 1961 Dec-62 May (Box 23, Folder 687)
  - "Vol. XXI", 1962 May-Sep (Box 23, Folder 688)
  - "Vol. XXII", 1962 Sep-63 Sep (Box 23, Folder 689)
  - "Vol. XXIII", 1963 Sep-64 Dec (Box 23, Folder 690)
  - "XXIV", 1964 Dec-66 Mar (Box 23, Folder 691)
    With some loose pages.
  - "Vol. XXV", 1966 Apr-67 Apr (Box 24, Folder 692)
  - "Vol. XXVI", 1967 Apr-68 Feb (Box 24, Folder 693)
  - "XXVII", 1968 Feb-Nov (Box 24, Folder 694)
  - Untitled, 1968 Nov-70 Aug (Box 24, Folder 695)
  - "Notebook", 1969 (Box 24, Folder 696)
  - "Being, From Now On, Greedy: Idylls and Anti-Idylls", 1969-71 (Box 25, Folder 697)
  - "Journal", 1970 Nov-71 Oct (Box 25, Folder 698)
  - "A Haphazard Journal", 1972 Oct-74 Aug (Box 25, Folder 699)
  - "Journal", 1974 Oct-76 Aug (Box 25, Folder 700)
  - "Some Aspects of 18th Century Nonconformity", 1976 Dec 11 (Box 25, Folder 701)
  - [ These the Companions ], [1976-77] (Box 26, Folder 702)
  - Untitled, 1979, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 703)
  - Untitled, 1980-86 (Box 26, Folder 704)
  - Untitled, 1981-86 (Box 26, Folder 705)
  - "Journal", 1982 Aug-84 Jan (Box 26, Folder 706)
  - "Journal", 1984 Mar-89 Dec (Box 26, Folder 707)
  - Untitled, 1985 Jan-92 Aug (Box 27, Folder 708)
  - Untitled, 1990 Feb-95 Jul (Box 27, Folder 709)
  - "A Notebook on Ezra Pound and Others" (Box 27, Folder 710)
- Other Papers, 1926-1992; Series IV; 0.6; (2 boxes)
  Series IV, Other Papers, is organized into two subseries: Personal Papers, and Subject Files. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by assigned title.
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Autobiographical article by Donald Davie from Contemporary Authors, printed version, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 711)
    - Clippings about Donald Davie, 1956-90, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 712)
    - Contract with British Broadcasting Corporation for reading by, and interview of, Donald Davie on 1992 Apr 28 (Box 28, Folder 713)
    - "A Conversation with Donald Davie," transcription, typescript, corrected, 1987 Dec (Box 28, Folder 714)
    - "Four Views," photography exhibition by Doreen Davie. Clippings and brochure, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 715)
    - Interview by John Barrell of Donald Davie at University of Essex, typescript (mimeograph), corrected, 1968 Apr (Box 28, Folder 716)
    - Photographs of Captain James Cook's cottage in Melbourne and Trinity College, [198-] (Box 28, Folder 717)
      Sent to DD by Tony Quagliano.
    - Photograph of four generations of Davies, [ca. 1926] (Box 28, Folder 718)
      With explanatory note by DD.
    - Postcard (unused) of the library at Universidade de Coimbra, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 719)
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - Bunting, Basil, 1982, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 720)
    - Cholmondeley Award for Poets (Box 28, Folder 721)
    - Cowper, William, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 722)
    - Larkin, Philip, 1967-73 (Box 28, Folder 723)
    - MacDiarmid, Hugh, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 724)
    - Orton, Job, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 725-730)
    - Poetry International, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 731)
    - Pound, Ezra, 1926-76, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 732)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1976 Apr 9 (Box 28, Folder 733)
    - Stafford, Clayton I., 1981 (Box 28, Folder 734)
    - University of Oxford Professorship of Poetry, 1978-81, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 735)
      Contains letters from Martin Dodsworth.
    - Yeats International Summer School, 1969-84, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 736-741)
      See also: Series I, Yeats International Summer School, box 8, folders 366-368
- Oversize, 1986
  - "God in Recent Poetry," proof, corrected (in Series II), 1986 (Box bsd, folder 742)
  - Czeslaw Milosz and the Insufficiency of Lyric, proof, corrected (in Series II) (Box bsd, folder 743)
  - Gifford, Henry. Poetry in a Divided World, proof, corrected (in Series II), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 744)
  - "Eliot in One Poet's Life," page proof (in Series II), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 745)
  - The Shires, galley proof, corrected (in Series II), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 746)
- Restricted, 0.4; (1 box)
  - Charles Tomlinson correspondence (Box 30, Folder 747-757)
    Conditions Governing Access
    This box was restricted during the lifetime of Charles Tomlinson. Since his death in 2015, the restriction has been lifted.
- Restricted Fragile, 0.6; (2 boxes)
  Boxes 31-32: Restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 2, folder 81 (Box 31, Folder 758)
  - Box 3, folder 155 (Box 31, Folder 759)
  - Box 4, folder 173 (Box 31, Folder 760)
  - Box 5, folder 221 (Box 31, Folder 761)
  - Box 5, folder 250 (Box 31, Folder 762)
  - Box 6, folder 262 (Box 31, Folder 763)
  - Box 7, folder 321 (Box 31, Folder 764)
  - Box 8, folder 350 (Box 31, Folder 765)
  - Box 8, folder 359 (Box 31, Folder 766)
  - Box 9, folder 393 (Box 31, Folder 767)
  - Box 9, folder 405 (Box 31, Folder 768)
  - Box 9, folder 408 (Box 31, Folder 769)
  - Box 9, folder 417 (Box 31, Folder 770)
  - Box 9, folder 418 (Box 31, Folder 771)
  - Box 9, folder 420 (Box 31, Folder 772)
  - Box 9, folder 425 (Box 31, Folder 773)
  - Box 10, folder 426 (Box 31, Folder 774)
  - Box 10, folder 429 and folder 431 (Box 31, Folder 775)
  - Box 10, folder 433 (Box 31, Folder 776)
  - Box 10, folder 434 (Box 31, Folder 777)
  - Box 10, folder 444 (Box 31, Folder 778)
  - Box 11, folder 449 (Box 31, Folder 779)
  - Box 11, folder 450 (Box 31, Folder 780)
  - Box 11, folder 452 (Box 31, Folder 781)
  - Box 11, folder 457 (Box 31, Folder 782)
  - Box 11, folder 463 (Box 31, Folder 783)
  - Box 12, folder 472 (Box 31, Folder 784)
  - Box 12, folder 473 (Box 31, Folder 785)
  - Box 12, folders 476-477 (Box 31, Folder 786)
  - Box 13, folder 491 (Box 31, Folder 787)
  - Box 13, folder 492 (Box 31, Folder 788)
  - Box 13, folder 493 (Box 31, Folder 789)
  - Box 13, folders 499-500 (Box 31, Folder 790)
  - Box 14, folder 504 (Box 31, Folder 791)
  - Box 14, folder 516 and folder 518 (Box 31, Folder 792)
  - Box 14, folder 519 (Box 31, Folder 793)
  - Box 15, folder 520 (Box 31, Folder 794)
  - Box 15, folder 524 (Box 31, Folder 795)
  - Box 15, folder 528 (Box 31, Folder 796)
  - Box 15, folder 532 (Box 31, Folder 797)
  - Box 16, folder 547 (Box 31, Folder 798)
  - Box 17, folder 549 (Box 31, Folder 799)
  - Box 17, folder 551 (Box 31, Folder 800)
  - Box 17, folder 553 (Box 31, Folder 801)
  - Box 17, folder 555 (Box 31, Folder 802)
  - Box 17, folder 560 (Box 31, Folder 803)
  - Box 17, folder 562 (Box 31, Folder 804)
  - Box 17, folder 568 (Box 31, Folder 805)
  - Box 17, folder 569 (Box 31, Folder 806)
  - Box 17, folder 582 (Box 31, Folder 807)
  - Box 17, folder 585 (Box 31, Folder 808)
  - Box 17, folder 586 (Box 31, Folder 809)
  - Box 17, folder 591 (Box 31, Folder 810)
  - Box 17, folder 598 (Box 31, Folder 811)
  - Box 17, folder 600 (Box 31, Folder 812)
  - Box 17, folder 605 (Box 31, Folder 813)
  - Box 17, folder 609 (Box 31, Folder 814)
  - Box 17, folder 615 (Box 31, Folder 815)
  - Box 19, folder 618 (Box 31, Folder 816)
  - Box 19, folder 619 (Box 31, Folder 817)
  - Box 19, folder 622 (Box 31, Folder 818)
  - Box 19, folder 625 (Box 32, Folder 819)
  - Box 19, folder 636 (Box 32, Folder 820)
  - Box 19, folder 639 (Box 32, Folder 821)
  - Box 19, folder 647 (Box 32, Folder 822)
  - Box 19, folder 652 (Box 32, Folder 823)
  - Box 19, folder 654 (Box 32, Folder 824)
  - Box 23, folder 687 (Box 32, Folder 825)
  - Box 28, folder 712 (Box 32, Folder 826)
  - Box 28, folder 715 (Box 32, Folder 827)
  - Box 28, folder 720 (Box 32, Folder 828)
  - Box 28, folder 723 (Box 32, Folder 829)
  - Box 28, folder 731 (Box 32, Folder 830)
  - Box 28, folder 732 (Box 32, Folder 831)
  - Box 28, folder 733 (Box 32, Folder 832)
  - Box 28, folder 735 (Box 32, Folder 833)
  - Box 29, folders 736-737 and folder 741 (Box 32, Folder 834)
- June 2013 Acquisition, 1940-2005; 12.88; (13 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged roughly in the order in which it was received.
  The June 2013 Acquisition consists of correspondence, photographs, personal papers, artwork, writings, printed materials, and audiovisual materials by or relating to Donald Davie.
  - Photographs, writings and drafts, journals, correspondence, photocopies, art, clippings, and typescripts, circa 1960s-1995 (Box 33)
    Includes "Auburns of the U.S.A.," material relating to The Canon, The Gadfly, Carcanet correspondence, Howard Warshaw material, and reviews of The Poetry of Survival (1992).
  - Correspondence, photocopies, writings and drafts, photographs, and other papers relating to Donald Davie, circa 1950s-1995 (Box 34)
    Includes papers relating to Michael Schmidt; letters to Reverend Harold Brimbaum; and and papers relating to Samuel Menashe. Also contains Donald Davie personal papers including honorary degrees, obituaries, biographies, tributes, and photographs.
  - Printed material, clippings, photocopies, and various reviews, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 35)
    Includes copies of The New Republic (1977 and 1987); The Eyesight of Wasps, by Osip Mandelshtam; various articles regarding Donald Davie and reviews of his poetry; clippings regarding "These the Companions" and "Dissentient Voice;" and information regarding student unrest at Essex University in 1968.